Get away from here!
So, where did it go?
I don't know!
Oh, here it is!
Hey there, Tom Thomas!
So, what's on the disc?
Hi there, Nolik!
Hi there, Simka!
It's a cartoon about Gulliver in the land of Lilliput.
My friend Genie let me borrow it.
I have it till tomorrow.
And what's the story about?
Well, it's about this guy who gets shipwrecked when people are just so teeny-tiny-tiny.
Fixies, you mean?
No, not Fixies. Lilliputians.
Lilliputians?
Uh-huh.
You know what, Simka?
I think that you Fixies might have come from those Lilliputians.
No way!
Our grandpa told us a completely different story of the Fixies.
When something is very well made,
then the saying goes that it was made with just a little bit of salt.
In old times craftsmen made things to last,
and in each appliance they would leave just a little piece of their soul.
Those little pieces of their soul would turn into tiny craftsmen called Fixies,
who would then make the appliance their home and take care of it every day.
And that's how the very first Fixies came about.
But as the years have passed, fewer things are being made by hand,
and more and more things are getting made by machines and factories.
That means there are less and less new Fixies coming from human souls.
Luckily, Fixies can fall in love with each other and have their own family,
raising their children and teaching them well,
so they'll grow up to become skillful and honest master Fixie repairmen.
So you're mistaken.
We're not Lilliputians at all.
We're Fixies!
Yeah, Fixies!
Listen, Tom Thomas, why don't you show us the movie?
Yeah, yeah! I want to learn about Lilliputians too!
Really? I do!
Sure, I'll show you.
Oh no! What's going on?
I broke it!
I can't give her back a disc that's messed up.
Don't panic!
We'll take a look at it.
Come lay it down over here.
Tom Thomas!
Why is this disc all covered in jelly?
Because I was touching it with my fingers.
I mean, what else?
It's obvious you don't know how a disc works at all!
And you know how it works?
Yeah, I know.
Yeah?
If we take a look at a digital disc through a powerful microscope,
we can see rows of tiny valleys of different lengths.
These valleys are actually a code
for the cartoons, games, or music recorded onto the disc.
Inside a disc player, a laser beam reads the code and helps turn it back into pictures and sounds.
But if you scratch the disc or smudge the disc with dirty fingers,
the laser can't read it and the disc won't play!
That's why you need to keep discs clean and stored in cases.
So that's why you should only hold discs along the edges.
And when you're done watching them, you have to put them back inside their boxes.
And what about this one?
Do we have to get rid of it?
Not so fast!
Nolik, this calls for a major cleaning!
Let's get the brooms!
Okay, Tom Thomas, check the disk!
There you go!
Now you're holding it right!
Hooray! The disk works fine!
Hooray! Now we can watch the movie about the Lilliputians!
Hey, Gulliver, why are you sitting there?
You've seen this movie already.
I know and what?
What-what! Look at that pile of disks!
Where do you need to put them?
In their boxes.